<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- Jiayuan Wen -->
<!-- DIGIT 110 -->

<?xml-model href="wen_8_29_xml-exercise-3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
    <Letter index="1" author="Marian Baldwin">      
        <CurrentLocation>On Board La Touraine,</CurrentLocation>
        <Date>June 30th, 1917.</Date>

        <Body>
            <Para p="1">
                <Sentence s="1">Even now that we are out of sight of land, it seems impossible that
                    I am actually off to France and, for the first time in my life, traveling
                    alone.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="2">Everything has happened so quickly since the American Fund for
                    French Wounded found an opening for me in Paris that I suppose I am still
                    somewhat dazed and bewildered.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="3">The fact that I don't know what it will all be like and that I can't
                    look ahead makes it easier to be happy and live in the present.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="4">Of course I have had a bit of a taste in New York of the work that
                    the A. F. F. W. is doing but its Headquarters in Paris will be different in some
                    ways I fancy.</Sentence>
            </Para>
            <Para p="2">
                <Sentence s="1">I can't get over how lucky I am to have this chance for I realize
                    how few girls of my age are getting across, and I understood the grit and pluck
                    which made you encourage me on my great adventure and send me along a path which
                    has proved so dangerous of late.</Sentence>
            </Para>
            <Para p="3">
                <Sentence s="1">As we drifted down the river, in the sunset glow with two absurd
                    tugs puffing alongside, I know that many eyes were moist and that the same
                    thought was in all our minds.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="2">How many of this ship's company will see that sky-line again! It was
                    very quiet, no one spoke much, and, little by little, the glow faded from the
                    sky and one star after another appeared.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="3">I knew that you would be looking at those same stars down in
                    Lakewood and that your thoughts and prayers were the same that filled my heart
                    at that moment.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="4">Somehow distance does not separate, after all.</Sentence>
            </Para>
            <Para p="4">
                <Sentence s="1">We waited near the Statue of Liberty until midnight—a rumor had it
                    that a "personage" was to come on board.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="2">This individual was shrouded in mystery until we put to sea when it
                    was given out that the party which had clambered aboard in the night was none
                    other than the Italian Mission.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="3">Our spirits rose at once for, what with Frank Sayre on the boat and
                    these distinguished Italian gentlemen, we shall doubtless be honored by a bigger
                    convoy and so doubly safe.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="4">However, thus far we have but two destroyers following
                    us.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="5">They can be seen distinctly outlined against the horizon, one on
                    each side, and seem to be the same somber gray which all ships are affecting in
                    this war.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="6">A sailor informed me this morning that we weren't in much danger for
                    the first four or five days but that after that I might see some excitement.
                    Here's hoping!</Sentence>
            </Para>
            <Para p="5">
                <Sentence s="1">I have a small inside cabin and my room-mate is quite a
                    character.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="2">She is a native of Haiti, voluble and very portly—has four large
                    pieces of baggage in our tiny stateroom, wears a costume which resembles a
                    Mother Hubbard and smokes countless thin cigarettes that smell like
                    incense!</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="3">When I appeared, there didn't seem to be much room for me but, as
                    she says, luckily I am small, and I was soon tucked into the upper berth with my
                    belongings!</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="4">She really isn't bad and after looking me over carefully told me
                    that she didn't think we would fight and from that time has beamed upon
                    me!</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="5">She is going over to join her son who has been fighting with the
                    French since the beginning of the war but will never go back to the Front now,
                    having lost some fingers off each hand.</Sentence>
                <Sentence s="6">She is so thankful, she says, that he hasn't lost more than his
                    fingers.</Sentence>
            </Para>
        </Body>
    </Letter>
    
    <Letter index="2" author="Marian Baldwin">
        <CurrentLocation>En route from Bordeaux to Paris,</CurrentLocation>
        <Date>July 18th, 1917.</Date>

        <Body>
            <Para p="1"> On landing yesterday <action>I went straight to the <location>Hôtel de France</location></action> and it
                certainly was good to have room to turn around in: as for a bed with real springs I
                greeted it with enthusiasm! <action>Towards evening Frank and I took a long walk about the
                    city</action>. A port town always interests me and <action>we saw it all at the loveliest time of
                day</action>. <scenery>The harbor was full of fishing smacks and small craft of all kinds and
                exquisite tones in the sails and rigging.</scenery> <scenery>The last rays of the sun cast a rosy hue
                over everything, making one think at once of <location>Venice</location> and the days before the war.</scenery>
                Later we wandered through some of the oldest parts of <location>Bordeaux</location> and I really felt
                that I was abroad again! <scenery>The narrow winding streets and cobblestones, with here and
                there an ancient façade or doorway and everywhere, in the poorest alleys, a bit of a
                vine or potted plant in the windows.</scenery> <question>How do they manage to make it all so
                picturesque and alluring?</question> </Para>

            <Para p="2"> <society>The women and the old men are doing everything and it is surprising to see
                the lady conductors</society>. <society>On this train they use women entirely, even in the dining car.</society>
                The war hasn't robbed them of vivacity or their beautiful complexions and I believe
                they are even prettier <apparance>in their simple black working clothes</apparance> than before. </Para>
            <!-- <Society> tag is sentence(s) describing social conditions, norms, enviroments -->

            <Para p="3"> We are at present passing through the famous vineyards and I have never
                seen the country look so beautiful. <scenery>The crops seem in perfect condition, thanks to
                the patient labor of these wonderful women, and the grain waves in profusion
                everywhere.</scenery> <action>I have longed for you at every turn</action>, how you would enjoy it all. <scenery>The
                poppies are in their prime and, as the train whirls by, they look like immense
                splashes of red -almost like stains of blood against the gold of the wheat.</scenery> </Para>

            <Para p="4"> <action>I have just come in from a very excellent meal in the dining car</action> -<action>the food
                was served promptly by two French girls of the peasant type</action> and with a speed that
                was wonderful, the car holding over thirty persons. </Para>
            
            <!-- Note: <action> only account for things the author or other people did actively/conciously with/witnout another person -->
        </Body>

        <locationSign>Paris</locationSign>
    </Letter>
    
    <Letter index="3" author="Marian Baldwin">
        <CurrentLocation>Aix,</CurrentLocation>
        <Date>May 10th, 1918.</Date>

        <Body>
            <Para p="1"><action>I've been very busy to-day learning a new dance</action>. <action>The weekly vaudeville troop
                arrived from <location>Paris</location> minus one number</action> and as <action>Mr. Carrell and I have danced on several
                Stunt Night programs</action>, <action>they asked us to fill in for the missing number</action>. So we are on
                for a week and we were so thankful that we had something that could be put right on
                to fill in. This little taste of stage life under such delightful auspices, is great
                fun. I have a dressing room all my own, No. 5, and Alice has been an angel, <action>acts as
                maid and helps me change my costume between our two numbers</action>. <action>We are billed with the
                professionals all over town</action>, "Miss Baldwin &amp; Mr. Carrell." It looked too
                absurd.</Para>

            <Para p="2"><action>I come on right after the "trained cats"</action> and, <action>while waiting in the wings</action>,
                <action>dodge the "snake charmer's" serpents</action>! <apparance>She has two about twelve yards long apiece and
                they wriggle and glide around behind the stage</apparance> and appear suddenly in the most
                unexpected manner! The snake charmer keeps them between times rolled up neatly in a
                lunch basket with a cloth drawn tightly over the top! <action>One of the acrobats told me
                she doped them</action>. Sometimes I get so interested behind the scenes that I almost forget
                to go on when my turn comes. These vaudeville artists are the most kind-hearted of
                mortals and have been so good to me and <action>encouraged me in the nicest way the first
                night, telling me to "keep smiling and not be scared."</action> One comedian has been
                especially good to me. -<apparance>He white-washes his face and wears a green nose and a suit
                with huge black and white checks</apparance>!</Para>
            
            <!-- Note: <action> only account for things the author did actively/conciously with/witnout another person -->
        </Body>
    </Letter>
</root>
